Spice and Wolf II
When I think about it, I can't help but believe that it was God who brought us together.
If not for you, I certainly wouldn't be sitting here drinking with a smile on my face.
I'll always be grateful to you too, Lawrence.
I'm glad we met.
No, the pleasure is all mine.
No, it's mine.
I've even asked you to help me smuggle gold.
To be frank, I didn't expect you to accept.
I was surprised I accepted myself, actually.
I sound strange, don't I?
But somehow, in my heart, I knew all along that one day I'd have to do something bold.
That I couldn't live my entire life under the protection of the Church.
That's why you're my savior, Lawrence.
I'm nothing of the sort.
Merchants are selfish creatures.
Well then, I suppose I am as well.
Drinking alone, Holo?
Have no fear.
I'm doing fine on my own.
Why don't you join our conversation?
What, are you already drunk?
I'm a wise wolf, said to have drunk an entire lake dry.
It'll take much more than a few cups to affect me.
All right.
You heard her.
I guess we'll leave her be for now.
Are you sure?
I'll join you after I've had a few more drinks.
You're on your own until then.
All right, we'll wait for you.
So, what were we talking about?
Ah, finally!
It looks delicious!
Thank you.
Would you like some?
Thanks, but I can serve myself.
You're supposed to be leaving me alone, remember?
Right.
What were we talking about?
Hmm, wasn't it about how we first met?
What about before that?
Oh! I think you mean the sheep and rock salt.
Yeah, that was it.
You know, I had no idea that sheep could be used to find rock salt.
It's true.
Sheep are fond of salt.
For example, if I were to put salt on a rock,
they would lick it endlessly.
So the story I heard might be true.
What story is that?
I've heard sheep are used for torture in a city to the east.
I didn't believe it then, but now...
Using sheep for torture?
Indeed.
It's quite an ingenious technique.
They tie the criminals up, put salt on their feet, and then bring the sheep in.
Salt on their feet, huh?
You will soon taste my wrath.
Sorry.
But if they put salt on their feet, then the sheep would...
They'd lick them enthusiastically, wouldn't they?
I think so.
At first, the tickling would make the criminals laugh so hard...
I'm dying! I gonna die!
Please stop!
That's a peculiar way to torture someone.
It certainly is.
The sheep would keep going, and as they licked their feet...
What do you think would happen?
What?
Since the criminals would be completely consumed by laughter,
they'd be transformed into good, perpetually smiling people.
All's well that ends well.
Is that a true story?
I made that last part up.
Oh, Lawrence!
But the rest of the story is true.
We'll never know what goes on in a sheep's mind.
Too true. Whenever I eat dried meat, they always seem desperate to lick my hands.
They're quite gentle, but how should I put it?
They don't understand the concept of moderation, so things can turn a bit scary.
On the other hand, your faithful knight seems to be quite obedient.
Who?
Oh! Well, Enek can be stubborn.
He refuses to listen at times.
Sorry.
He seems quite well-trained, though.
It goes to show how skilled of a shepherdess you are.
Not at all.
What is it, Holo?
Drunk already?
Absolutely not.
Sure looks that way.
I can't leave you alone for a minute.
As if I'd...
be drunk...
after only three cups...
H-Holo?
Maybe it's because I lived alone in the wheat fields for so many hundreds of years...
The days rolled by so peacefully,
with no distinction between today or the day before it,
or tomorrow, or the days that followed.
And yet, certain days would stand out in my mind:
The Harvest Festival that was held once a year.
The Seed Sowing Festival, twice a year.
The festival where they would pray away the rain.
The festival where they would pray away the wind.
But the rest of the year was dull and full of mundane, uncelebrated days.
If I let my attention slip, sometimes I might find that what was a seedling had grown into a fine tree.
But now, every day of our travels brings new experiences.
The few months I've spent with this young merchant
are more vivid than all the decades that I spent in the wheat.
We might have heated arguments in the morning,
only to reconcile by lunch, when I'd tease him as he wiped breadcrumbs from my mouth.
In the evening, we'd get into another fight over our meal,
but at night, we'd speak peacefully of the days to come.
I've traveled with humans several times before,
but now I don't have time to even think of those days.
What did he do yesterday?
How was he this morning?
I'm too busy with these thoughts to consider anything else.
It was only in the early days that I would sometimes remember my homeland and find myself crying.
Thanks to these ever-exciting days,
I have no time to feel down.
To say this journey wasn't fun would be a lie.
Indeed, I'm a bit worried that I may be having too much fun.
Heavy...
Why am I in the inn?
Wh-What was that?
If that was real, I'll die of shame.
It must've been a nightmare.
I'll pretend it never happened.
I wonder why...
I lower my guard every time he gives me that silly look.
I get angry when I dislike his attitude, and I laugh when he's funny.
I've shamed the title of wise wolf.
Yes, this is better.
This is the position I should take to immediately react to any enemy attacks.
That simpleton, on the other hand...
He's no better than a stupid cat.
Well, maybe being so defenseless and thickheaded is what you need to live in the human world.
Why isn't he here now?
How could he leave me alone at a time like this?
He's so useless.
What's wrong with me?
Oh, you're finally back?
Why did you hide that you're feeling ill?
Well...
You're not a child.
Don't claim you didn't notice before you collapsed.
What would you have done if we were on the road?
You might not know this,
but getting sick in the middle of a forest or the wilderness could mean death.
I'm really worried about you.
Sorry.
So, how do you feel?
It's nothing serious.
I'm just tired.
It's not some strange illness, is it?
Not at all.
Good...
Thank God.
I'm very relieved to hear it.
You're overreacting.
Well, the more I thought about it, the more I worried.
And I thought... that...
What?
Tell me.
Well, I thought the onions you ate might've made you sick.
I'm not a dog.
Of course not.
You're the wise wolf!
I'm disappointed that I couldn't enjoy the food and drink, though.
I'm a merchant, you know.
That's a mistake I'd never make.
I asked to take the leftovers with me.
Really?
Of course!
I'll bring them to you now.
I'd like to, anyway.
But you have a fever.
You're completely exhausted, aren't you?
It's your fault!
Huh?
Your fingers are hard, like the tip of a wolf's nose.
And when we wolves rub our noses together, it's like when you humans...
I can't say it.
No, please explain.
It's nothing!
Just forget it!
I'll save your meal for when you feel better.
Sleep well.
Lawrence!
You're so warm...
Holo, are you awake?
Can't you tell?
How do you feel?
I can't sit up.
Honestly?
It's certainly true that you look as pale as a sheltered princess.
I'm starving.
That's a good sign.
Then I'll get some porridge for you.
I'm thirsty too.
Is that water?
Yes... well, no.
Since you had a fever last night, I bought apple cider.
Really?!
H-Hey, are you all right?
If only you were usually even half this peaceable.
When I sleep peacefully in the wagon,
you get angry with me.
Well, it isn't fair if I'm the only one awake, now is it?
And if I were always a meek little lamb,
you'd eat my share of the food.
I'm a grown man. I need to eat more than you.
Then, to counter that, I should have an even bigger attitude.
What is it?
It doesn't taste right...
Oh, that's because I diluted it.
Too much!
I thought my nose had gone stupid.
Diluted apple cider is good for fevers.
Didn't you know that?
I am the wise wolf,
so I know enough about the world to know there are things I don't know.
Diseases develop when the body's equilibrium is upset,
like the ebb and flow of the tide.
So when that happens, you restore the body's balance by regulating its four states.
Four states?
Yes!
Hot and cold, dry and wet. These are the four states.
All right. And?
You can regulate them by what you choose to eat or drink.
You had a fever, so you needed something cold.
That's why I brought you apple cider!
I would rather eat a real apple.
That wouldn't help.
Apples are cold, yes, but they're dry.
Sick people are too dry, so you need to get them wet foods.
Which means you needed something to drink.
Even having alcohol would make you feel better,
but strong drinks are hot, so they should be diluted.
So, what else are you planning to make me eat?
Good question.
When fatigue causes a fever, you need to cool your body down first.
But since your body's too dry,
you need to get it wet again.
But that cools you down further, and if people get too cold they get depressed.
So, how about wheat porridge with hot sheep's milk,
mixed with apple slices and goat's cheese?
Sounds perfect!
I'd love that!
Hey now...
Are you sure you haven't recovered already?
I-I feel dizzy...
Holo!
Hurry with that food, okay?
I'll be right back.
I want a big bowl!
Lawrence!
Can you sit up?
No...
I hope you'll take care of me when I'm sick.
I will, if you don't mind treatment the way it's done in Yoitsu.
I'll think about it.
Worry not, I have a good nose.
I'll take action before you even get sick.
I'm sorry for not noticing,
but you should've told me.
You know how thickheaded I'm supposed to be.
I might have a much more serious disease,
but I'm sure you'd fail to notice in any case.
Nothing.
Give me the food!
If you can eat all this, you'll be fine.
You'll be fully recovered in two days at most.
Once we leave this town, we'll be stuck in the wagon for quite a while.
I'm sorry.
Take your time to recover.
I gave up on swift travel when I picked you up.
And since I compensated and apologized to everyone I begged money from,
my reputation in this city's recovered.
In fact, it's improved.
When you consider that, I don't mind being delayed two or three days.
Plus, there are many places I'd still like to visit in this town.
Don't leave—
I mean, you know...
The inn is too quiet.
You're right.
We should talk about everything you'd like to feast on tonight.
That's not what...
Do you have any ideas?
Be as detailed as you like, but keep in mind that I need to get to the market before it closes.
You seem better, but anything heavy is still out of the question.
So no meat?
Definitely not.
How about porridge, or soup with bread?
All right, then I want what I just had.
It had sheep's milk, right?
The sweet scent and strong taste were delicious.
It'll do just fine!
Sheep's milk, huh?
Is that a problem?
It can sour quickly, so the price for good milk goes up in the afternoon.
You want it fresh, I assume.
Of course!
Then I should ask Norah to help me find some again.
When it comes to this sort of thing,
shepherds are quite—
W-Well, if I ask her, I'll be able to get my hands on the best milk.
If you just spend a bit more, you can get it without relying on her!
Th-That might be true, but...
But what?!
Wh—
Why do you hold a grudge against Norah?
What?
Wh-What did you just say?
W-Well, it's just that...
I don't know what shepherds did to you in the past,
and I can understand that, as a wolf,
you can't bring yourself to like them,
but you don't have to bare your fangs at her so much.
She's good-natured, and there are exceptions to every rule, right?
You...
W-What?
Sorry, I was in the wrong.
So it's okay, then?
Well, how should I put it?
I suppose it's all right.
It's just who you are.
What?
I'm looking forward to the sheep's milk.
Norah came to see you.
How are you feeling?
Oh, just fine. It's just a bit of fatigue.
But I wouldn't mind talking with you for a bit.
There's something I've always wanted to ask you.
Go ahead.
I hope I have the answer.
What is the trick to leading sheep?
A generous and patient heart.
The wind's picking up.
You're right, surely.
Sheep always think they're so clever, after all.
Talking about something interesting?
N-No...
It's our little secret. Just us girls.
Oh, I see...
Wolf and Amber Melancholy
And so we who are falling in love
Miss each other just
before it happens
Even though I want to tell you,
no words come out
Take me,
take me,
to the perfect world
If I take the path
up to the sky
I'll find a lake
of flowing comets
Because we are incomplete,
We can't help hurting each other
If you would
just embrace me,
I feel like we
could truly touch
If we could
just embrace...
My dearest
is surely beside me
The most important thing
is always beside me
Next time: Wolf and a Sudden Rift.